[mysterious music playing]
-[water trickling]
-[wind whistling]
[train horn blowing]
[woman 1] Our latest cold case is
from the evening of May 11th, 1973.
At approximately 12:48 a.m.
in the Brick Lane section of East London,
a man was walking back from the pub
to the home of his girlfriend,
Angela Hughes,
when he heard two voices emanating
from her second-floor window.
[woman 2 screams]
[man grunting]
[screaming]
Hey, stop! You!
[panting]
Stop!
[woman 1] When the police arrived,
Angela Hughes was already dead.
They searched her apartment,
but nothing had been stolen.
[man] Well, I think it stinks.
What stinks, Ron?
Well, where's the motive? For a robbery.
They were a broke young couple.
Makes no sense.
Very good point.
And have I understood correctly,
the only person
to actually see this masked man
was the boyfriend?
According to the police report, yes.
Who was the boyfriend?
Does he have a name?
Peter Mercer. 25 years old. Mechanic.
Discharged from the army
with a knee injury.
It was a gunshot wound in the field.
Oh, good chance of unprocessed trauma.
-Can cause erratic behavior.
-Hmm.
Mercer chased the masked man
but couldn't catch him.
Then he disappeared.
Short while after. Never seen again.
See? Stinks.
Stinks like a rat up a drainpipe.
Um, do you think there's any way
the poor girl could have been saved?
I don't know. It's hard to tell.
The report claims it was the knife wound
that killed her, not the fall.
So that's murder.
Well, Mercer would have known
basic first aid.
-Why didn't he save her? Plonker.
-[scoffs]
He told the police she died on the spot.
But I know it takes time to bleed out.
I confess I'm a little stumped.
-Yeah?
-But this is a particularly tough one.
Makes the case of the dismembered body
in the postbox look like child's play.
Yes. What we need now
is some medical expertise.
[bright music playing]
[birds chirping]
[woman 1] So this is
the famous Coopers Chase. Hm.
[woman 2] I'll give you a tour.
Over there is the hospice wing
for when things get a bit, well, you know.
Ah, we have archery classes,
and one of the residents won
the silver medal in the 1972 Olympics.
Nice one! Well done. Yes, that's it.
[woman 2] You must admit,
Joanna, it is beautiful.
And we even have llamas
as support animals.
Everybody's got llamas these days, Mum.
-Oh.
-You should be careful.
Llamas can be very temperamental.
Biting, spitting in your face.
[llama grunting]
Oh well, I've known humans to do that
under severe stress too.
Look, I want to show you the jigsaw room.
[man] So did she bleed to death
from the stab wound or the fall?
-Oh my God.
-[intriguing music playing]
Oh, hello.
Isn't this room usually for jigsaws?
Not on a Thursday, no.
Oh.
Okay. Sorry.
We'll leave you to it.
Hmm.
-Mum?
-Oh.
[whispers] Must be
the Agatha Christie club or something.
[intriguing music intensifies]
-I really do have to get back on the road.
-Oh.
Traffic is murder,
and I'm taking a very important client
to the opera tonight.
-[exhales]
-Look, Mum.
-I think it's a mistake, you living here.
-What?
Why don't you let me buy you
a little flat near me?
Well, you know, nearish.
Joanna, I need to be somewhere
where I have a chance to make new friends.
How can I possibly do that
living on my own in Hackney,
surrounded by, I don't know,
hipsters and vegan bakeries?
-They don't want an old woman around.
-All right, fine.
I just… I want you to be happy.
Since Dad died…
-Well, I worry about you, that's all.
-I'm fine.
Oh.
[door opening]
-Drive safely.
-[Joanna] Will do.
[door closing]
I do hope I'm right about this, Gerry.
I'm not used to making big decisions
on my own.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday to… ♪
Oh, there she is.
♪ Happy birthday… ♪
-[woman] Yeah. No. It could be--
-So it must be a two in here.
-Are you a nurse?
-Sorry, what?
It's just that you didn't flinch
at those photos earlier on,
so I'm thinking that maybe you have
some sort of medical training.
You could've been a doctor,
but, uh, female doctors were very rare
when we were young,
so I'm thinking a trauma nurse,
seen a lot of fatal injuries.
Am I close?
Bang on target.
-Um…
-Oh. Oh, I'm sorry, I'm Elizabeth.
Ibrahim.
Mmm. Ron.
-I'm Joyce.
-Joyce.
So, Joyce, would you take a look
at that for me, please?
Dear God.
Uh, perhaps we could leave
the finer details for later.
Could that girl have survived
an injury like that?
Well, that would depend partly
on how much she weighed.
It is a lot of blood.
Forty-six kilos.
Yes, then I think she could have survived,
providing she had--
Look, how long is all this kerfuffle
going to last?
We're doing the extra-hard Sudoku here.
Joyce, would you care to join us
to discuss things further?
Privately?
Oh, all right.
But who is "us"?
I'm sorry, how rude of me.
We're the Thursday Murder Club.
[intriguing music playing]
[intriguing music intensifies]
[phone ringing]
Give me some good news, Lloyd.
I'm not paying you a small fortune
to get me screwed over.
[Lloyd] Good morning, Ian.
Okay, so here's the latest.
Mrs. Ventham says she wants
the car and the house
and the apartment in Majorca.
My God, it was one shag!
This is an overreaction
of dickish proportions!
And she's no angel either, by the way.
I have proof of that now. Leverage.
[Lloyd] Well, overreaction or not,
you need to buckle up, Ian.
Gemma is serious about this divorce,
and she's coming at you
with everything she's got.
[screams]
[inhaling] Right.
Ian.
So, uh, why is all this so urgent?
Why are we meeting in… in private, huh?
I need to maximize my assets,
now more than ever.
So I'm cracking on
with the cemetery clearance,
paperwork or no paperwork.
Better to seek forgiveness
than ask permission, right?
Then we demolish the church.
We use the ground for luxury flats.
Ah, no, no, no. What about the old people?
They will not like it.
They don't have to like it.
They'll be gone.
And I'll use the original building
as an event space.
But they will not leave so easily.
You know, many of them were very strong,
very powerful in their time.
It's not their time, is it? It's my time.
And it's my bloody land.
No, I'm not worried
about the cantankerous old farts.
The only real issue is Tony Curran.
-[footsteps approaching]
-Why?
-[waitress] There you are, Mr. Ventham.
-Thank you.
Tony is part owner in Coopers Chase.
He will make a lot of money too, no?
Yeah, he would if he'd agree to it.
But he's being a stubborn prick as always.
His Auntie Maud is a resident,
and he doesn't want her disturbed.
So if he refused to do it,
who will take job?
[suspenseful music playing]
Ah, me?
You like that?
Be the boss? Make more money?
Yes, uh, sure.
Yeah, it would be good for me.
My mother is very sick back in Poland,
and, you know, I need to send
extra money for her care. But…
Bogdan, the diggers are booked
for Monday morning.
All you need to do is show up
at the cemetery and break ground,
you get a nice fat payday.
More than enough money
to look after your mum back in Romania.
-Poland.
-Poland. Okay, all right.
Tony Curran is a dangerous man,
mixed up in dangerous things.
If you fire him,
maybe he kill you.
Oh. Bogdan. [chuckles]
I'm an experienced mixed martial artist,
all right?
Regional level.
-[Bogdan] Mm.
-Yes, I'm a pretty dangerous man myself.
Mm-hmm.
Now, do we have a deal or not?
[exhales sharply]
Okay, okay. I do it.
-We have a deal. Yeah.
-Yeah!
Good morning, Auntie Maud.
My favorite!
Don't you look lovely today, girl?
Oh, you're a good boy, Tone.
-Morning, Tony. Hello, mate. How are you?
-Ah, Ron. Good morning, mate.
I'd like to introduce you to Joyce here.
She's just joined us.
-Oh, welcome to Coopers Chase, Joyce.
-Oh, thank you.
Morning, Maud.
[Maud] Mmm.
[chuckling]
Who is that?
Tony Curran, co-owner of Coopers Chase
with Ian Ventham.
He bought the run-down convent
for cash back in the '80s.
Got a pretty good deal on it too.
Yeah, I should say.
Did the early renovation himself,
he said, with his bare hands.
Then he brought in Ventham
for the extra capital to finish the job.
-So they're business partners?
-Yeah.
-He seems a bit…
-Rough, yes, but don't worry.
Tony's on our side.
That's the most important thing.
What do you mean, on our side?
Rumor has it, Ian Ventham wants
to get rid of Coopers Chase.
What? Why?
Build luxury flats. Send us all packing.
But I've only just moved in.
Oh, that's not gonna fly with Tony, is it?
Not while Auntie Maud is still kicking.
So Tony Curran
is quite important to us in his way.
As is Aunt Maud.
-Let's have some of that cake, shall we?
-Let's.
[chuckles]
Mmm. Oh.
The Thursday Murder Club has been in need
of medical expertise for some time now.
So, Joyce, we would like you to join us,
but, um, on a temporary basis.
-It all sounds rather fun.
-[Ibrahim chuckles]
Bloody world-class cake, Joyce.
I could get used to this, you know.
Don't get too used to it, Ron.
Give your statins a fighting chance.
It is exceedingly delicious cake though.
-I'll absolutely concede that.
-Thank you.
I made it for my daughter, but apparently
she's perimenopausal and can't eat it.
Well, if I could drag everyone's attention
away from the cake for just one moment…
-Joyce?
-Yes?
[clearing throat]
-The picture you saw earlier on…
-Mm.
…of the murdered woman
is from our current cold case.
Angela Hughes, "the case of the woman
in white who fell out of the window."
-Ah.
-[Elizabeth] Yes.
The police report states
Angela's boyfriend, Peter Mercer,
was questioned
and soon released by the police.
They felt he was a good bloke
and believed his story about the intruder.
However, there was one police officer,
DI Penny Gray,
the only woman on the force at the time,
who wanted to bring him in
for re-questioning, but she was refused.
The boys' club closed ranks,
and the next thing we know is
that he'd vanished
and was never heard from again.
Case closed.
Until now.
May I ask, how did you get these cases?
I mean, surely these files
are all confidential.
Yes. Yes, well, they…
they come from the other founding member
of our group
and a very close friend of mine, Penny.
Ah, DI Penny Gray, who wanted
to further question Peter Mercer.
Yes, exactly the same.
How exciting.
Will she be joining us next week?
No, she won't be joining us.
-[somber music playing]
-Penny lives in the hospice wing now.
Oh.
[softly] Sorry.
Thank you.
Darling, I thought I should bring you
up to speed on our latest cold case.
Ibrahim is insisting we call it
"the case of the woman in white
who fell out of the window."
[laughing] Really? Catchy, no?
But it's a tricky one, this one.
You'd love it.
The time it took the poor girl
to bleed to death, that's the key.
[inhales sharply]
But we've had a bit of luck.
-Luck?
-Yes. An eager helper.
An ex-nurse has just moved in. Joyce.
She's nice enough.
A bit simple, really, actually.
But, um… but she knows
all about knife wounds and so on.
Everybody has their uses.
Oh, Pen, I do wish
you could help us with this case.
It's a good one. I can't believe
you didn't suggest it yourself before you…
[clicks tongue] Oh.
[inhales deeply]
John, do you think she can hear us?
Some days I pray that she can,
and some days I pray that she can't.
I just turn up and read to her.
-Hm. Plenty of murder mysteries, I hope.
-Of course.
She was going crazy with boredom
before you moved in here.
The Thursday Murder Club kept her sane.
You were quite the team.
[chuckles softly]
How is Stephen?
Oh, you know.
That's a… That's a slope, isn't it?
That type of dementia.
And he's not climbing back up.
He has his good days and his bad days.
And sometimes he's there,
my Stephen, as I love him. Smart, clear.
And then I turn around
and he's gone again.
Gone.
Cherish the good moments.
-Stephen, I'm back.
-[Stephen] Oh, hello, love.
You have a good day?
Yes, fine, thanks. You?
Yes.
-The lady came with my lunch.
-Hm, what was it?
Oh, good God.
Slipped my mind. Uh…
Whatever it was, it was delicious.
[Stephen] Lunch today was chicken pie
with leeks and boiled potatoes.
Mmm.
[Stephen] Lovely.
Sounds good.
-What are you reading?
-Well, I was…
[inhales deeply]
I was looking in the garden earlier
and I saw a magpie, just the one.
And it worried me. So I looked it up,
and do you know they mate for life?
-[clock chiming]
-Isn't that lovely?
Just like us.
[chuckling]
[Elizabeth chuckles]
[inhales] Oh, God, look at the time.
No, I'm late. Meeting with my publisher.
-No, it's all right.
-What?
There's no rush.
I'll make you a cup of tea first. Hmm?
-Maybe a little nap. [chuckles]
-[gasps] Yes, lovely.
[chuckles softly]
[sniffles]
[melancholy music playing]
[pills rattling]
[indistinct chatter]
[breathlessly] Hi, everyone. Um…
I'm sorry I'm late. I… [inhales deeply]
I'm PC Donna De Freitas
from Fairhaven Police Station.
And today I'm here to talk to you about…
practical tips for home security.
-[grumbling]
-Are you a real police officer?
Of course she's a real police officer,
Marjorie. Behave yourself now. [chuckles]
Yes, I am indeed a real police officer.
Good. Well, I have a question for you,
a proper one.
-Now…
-Okay.
If a man brutally murdered his girlfriend
and then disappeared,
how long would you keep
the investigation open
before declaring him a missing person?
-Mm.
-[Donna] Um…
Uh…
Um, well, uh…
I'm not quite sure what that has to do
with safety in the home.
[scoffs]
I think we're all hoping this isn't going
to be some stodgy talk about door locks.
[laughing]
Yeah, we've all heard about ID cards.
"Are you really from the gas board,
or are you a burglar?" You know.
Oh. [laughs] Yeah.
I'd welcome a burglar.
Be nice to have a visitor.
-Oh.
-[man coughing]
[Donna] Um… Um…
Well, actually,
I wanted to talk to you guys
about safety alert bracelets.
[clanging]
Oh.
[whispers] No, no.
No!
-That's my car!
-I'm so sorry.
I'm afraid our parking committee here
take their duties rather seriously.
-Uh-huh. They're fascists.
-But they can't do that! I'm the police.
Even if you were the king of England,
they wouldn't give a shit.
Yes, you won't be going anywhere
for at least an hour, I'm afraid.
[sighing]
Would you care to join us for lunch?
[Ron] Mm.
-Shall we order a bottle of each?
-Oh yeah.
-Bottle each of what?
-Color. Red and white. Wine.
Oh. I mean, it's a…
It's a little bit early for me.
Uh-huh. It's not early
if you've been awake since 5:30.
Guess how old I am.
-[scoffs]
-Uh…
-78?
-[coughs]
-But you don't look it.
-I do Pilates.
Oh, well, like I said,
you don't look a day over 65,
but the hands, they're always a giveaway.
Ah, good police work, that.
So, PC De Freitas, is this your first job?
Oh, no, no.
I was at Met Police in London for a bit,
and then I left and moved here.
How do you like it so far?
A bit boring, perhaps?
[laughs nervously] Um…
It's all right. You're safe with us.
Well, then…
Yes. Yes, I am bored out of my head
doing traffic offenses all day.
-[Ron] Ha!
-[laughing]
So, are you single? Are you married?
-Confirmed bachelor.
-Mm.
Divorced. Twice.
Widowed.
Elizabeth is married, though,
to the lovely Stephen.
Oh, really? Will he be joining us?
No, he's got a writing deadline.
Stephen's a published author.
-Really?
-Mm.
And what did you do before you retired?
Psychiatrist. I specialized
in helping war veterans with PTSD.
And, uh, you, Ron?
Hm? Oh, trade unionist. [chuckles]
Not just any trade unionist, Ron.
The trade unionist.
Known in his day as Red Ron.
Indeed, yeah. If it was a picket line,
a strike, or a sit-in, you know,
I was there around the old brazier,
rallying the troops.
-Mm.
-[chuckles]
-Great days. Great days.
-Hm.
And, uh, you, Joyce?
Oh, nothing to see here.
I was a nurse, then a mum,
then a nurse again.
My daughter, Joanna,
is the interesting one of the family.
She runs a hedge fund,
if you know what that is.
-No.
-[Ron] No idea.
-[Joyce] Me neither.
-[Donna, Ibrahim laugh]
And you, Elizabeth?
What did you do?
[chuckles]
International affairs.
Oh. [giggles] Like a diplomat?
Mm…
Let's just say
I have a wide portfolio of skills.
-[waitress] May I?
-Ah, the wine. Lovely, thank you.
I'll have some of that.
So, what have we got today?
Let's have a look.
-[Ibrahim] I'm going to order for you.
-[Ron] You are?
Come on, Jackie, keep up!
[bright music playing]
This place is amazing.
Really makes me look forward
to getting old.
Ha!
I mean, when I, like,
reach the later chapters of my life.
Yes, Coopers Chase is exceptional.
-[man] Oi, oi!
-We're incredibly lucky…
-Ah, there he is.
-Oh, it's Jason.
How you doing, Pops?
Oh, good, son.
All the better for seeing you.
-[man laughs]
-Is that Jason Ritchie?
Yes, our very own celebrity. Ron's son.
He visits his dad
two or three times a week.
-[chuckles]
-Oh, Ibsy.
-Jason.
-Hello, Jason.
-Elizabeth.
-Yeah, Jason, this is PC Donna De Freitas.
-All right? How you doing?
-[Donna] Hi.
Yes, it's so nice to meet you.
Yeah, I was a big-- I am a-- a big fan.
You know, I've seen all your fights.
Oh.
So, um, what are you up to these days
after the injury?
Just a few TV appearances here and there.
Oh, yeah.
He was the ultimate champion
back in the day, weren't you, son?
-She knows, Dad.
-Yeah.
Uh, Jason, this is Joyce.
She's just arrived.
Can I just say,
I thought you were absolutely marvelous
on Celebrity MasterChef.
-Oh, thank you very much, Joyce.
-[Joyce] Mm-hmm.
[breathily] So…
what are you doing next, Jason?
Well, I just started rehearsals
for Dancing on Ice.
Oh! That's a little bit like a sport,
isn't it?
[inhales deeply]
Yeah.
Um, well, thank you so much
for lunch. Thank you.
Oh. [giggles]
-Thank you. Take care.
-All the best now. See you.
-Bye. Bye.
-[Jason] Yeah, laters.
-Nice girl.
-Mm.
-Could be useful.
-[car engine starts]
[Ian] Tony, mate, leave it.
[Tony] I won't let you get away with this.
Listen, there's nothing to get away with.
There's nothing dodgy.
It's all in our favor. Read the contract.
-The contract?
-Yeah!
You're gonna get that Bogdan,
the Polish worker, in there, ain't you?
Well, you ain't doing nothing
while my Aunt Maud's still alive.
-I'll see you in court!
-Anytime.
-Oh dear.
-[Ian] I'll be ready.
What do you think that's all about?
-Money.
-[car engine starting]
[inhales] Always comes down
to money in the end.
[tense music playing]
Tony. Tony, what's going on?
What's going on, Liz? Him.
Ventham, that's what's going on.
Reckons he's gonna dig up the cemetery
and turn it into luxury flats.
-So the rumors were true?
-The noise will be awful!
Yes, but what about the main building?
What about our apartments?
Turning it into an event space.
-[gasps]
-God.
-Ron.
-Yeah.
-What can we do about this?
-Call a residents' meeting.
It's in our lease contracts.
He has to consult us first.
But isn't there something
you can do as co-owner?
Oh, there's plenty.
There's plenty I can do.
Let me reassure you,
I'll do everything in my power
to save this place and you lovely people.
You don't mess with the Currans.
And he's about to find out.
Let me tell you.
We've got a fight on our hands.
[dramatic music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[residents booing]
[man] Shame on you!
[booing continues]
[indistinct shouting]
-Whoa, whoa, what are you doing? Hey!
-Oh, you plonker!
Well, okay.
[booing fades]
Okay, full house.
Um, first of all, let me quote Confucius.
Oh, here's a quote.
Your words, Mr. Ventham, not mine.
"Ventham Investments, Inc. may only
develop further residential possibilities
in consultation
with current residents of Coopers Chase."
[residents murmuring]
Yeah, this is a consultation.
You are the residents.
Consult all you like
for the next ten minutes.
This is not a consultation.
It's an ambush!
We know you intend to do away
with the entire retirement community.
Yeah, and chuck us out on the street.
Oh, come on. No, no, no, come on.
Not out on the street.
You will all be compensated and rehoused.
But we want to be at Coopers Chase.
We have signed leases.
Lifetime leases.
Yeah, and you all appear to be immortal.
However, if you read the contract,
you will see
there is a clause which says--
The point is, Mr. Ventham,
we love it here.
-[residents] Yeah!
-This is our home. These are our friends.
And there are residents here
whose partners need special care.
-Or don't have family in this country.
-[sighs]
What are you going to do about the llamas?
They're completely out of control,
like bloody rabbits.
Well, I made a large contribution
to the donkey sanctuary,
and they're gonna take them, so…
Oh, and is that what you want
to do with all of us too, huh?
[residents murmuring]
Anyway, I'm their vet.
I take care of them.
And you can't do things like that
without consulting me first.
Look, the fact of the matter is,
this is my land.
Okay? I'm perfectly entitled
to do whatever I want with it.
You shouldn't be digging up
sacred graves, disturbing them,
just to make a quick buck.
It's a sin.
Whoo! [laughs]
[residents murmuring]
I didn't know Father Mackie
could get so worked up.
He tends to that cemetery every day.
He must feel his faith is being belittled.
[Ron] Guess so.
All right. In the absence of God himself
making an appearance, that's all.
Time's up. Diggers start on Monday.
Thank you very much.
[residents clamoring]
[engine revving]
[Tony] He's picked on the wrong dude
if he thinks
he's gonna get away with this.
-I told him straight.
-[man on phone] Really? [chuckles]
Yeah, I said, "Listen here, Ventham."
I said, "You think you're gonna employ
that Polish twat over me,
you got another thing coming."
[man] Okay. Okay, Tony.
Let's not do anything rash.
You need to keep your wits about you.
Mate, I'm gonna
have to call you back, yeah?
-Okay, cheers.
-Ta-ta.
[ominous music playing]
[groans]
[footsteps descending heavily]
[mysterious music playing]
What are you doing here?
-[siren blaring]
-[indistinct radio chatter]
So, the victim appears
to have been bludgeoned to death.
No sign of a murder weapon.
[police officer speaking indistinctly]
Message received. Sending backup.
[radio host] It's breakfast
with KNT1. Radio in Kent.
In breaking news, the body of Tony Curran,
a local businessman and contractor,
was found at his home yesterday morning.
He appears
to have been bludgeoned to death.
At this time, there are no suspects.
Police say it is an ongoing investigation.
["Disco Inferno" by The Trammps playing]
[panting]
Elizabeth? Elizabeth?
We need to meet
outside the jigsaw room, immediately!
I'm calling an emergency meeting
right now!
What on earth?
[fitness instructor] Yes!
Let's go, everyone. Left! Right!
Left! Right!
♪ Burn baby burn
Burn that mother down… ♪
-Ron!
-[Ron] Yeah?
We've got to have a meeting.
Get out of the pool, now!
What's all this about, Joyce?
I was doing my yoga.
You can't salute the sun twice in one day.
You know, temporary members
of the TMC aren't supposed
to call extraordinary meetings.
There's been a murder! An actual murder!
-What?
-Who?
Tony Curran! He was killed
in his house yesterday morning.
[inhales] Now we've got
a real case to solve.
Isn't it wonderful?
-No, Joyce, it's not wonderful.
-If Tony Curran is dead…
Who's going to protect Coopers Chase
from being destroyed?
Ventham can do what he wants.
Yes, of course. I'm very sorry about Tony.
Obviously, RIP and all that.
-Who'd want to kill Tony Curran?
-Mm-hmm. And how do we catch them?
The police are probably
making a list of suspects right now.
What we need is a man,
or a woman, on the inside.
Oh, and I think we know just the person.
[inspector] Right, listen up, gentlemen.
Cause of death, it's a nasty one,
blunt trauma
to the right side of the head.
The place was turned over,
possibly a robbery gone wrong,
but there was no sign of a forced entry.
The last phone call he made
was to an unlisted number,
burner phone most likely.
Uh, there was various items
on the floor and sideboard.
Documents, bills, contracts, including…
this photo.
Now, it--
Yeah, no, leave the tray, Constable.
I'm sure you've got
other important duties to attend to.
Yes.
Of course.
[tray thuds on table]
-[quietly] Very important duties.
-Right…
Tea's not gonna make itself.
[phone ringing]
-Hello?
-Joyce, you ready?
[inhales] Nearly.
["Bang a Gong (Get It On)"
by T. Rex playing]
-See you at the bus stop.
-Okay.
♪ Well, you're dirty and sweet ♪
♪ Clad in black
Don't look back ♪
♪ And I love you ♪
♪ You're dirty, sweet
And you're my girl… ♪
There you go. How's that? Too much?
No, no, no, no, not at all.
It looks, um… It's very realistic.
Hello?
[inhales deeply]
Fairhaven Police Station. Of course.
I'm Dr. Ibrahim Arif.
Correct.
My good friend, Ron Ritchie,
has some rather important information
about the murder of Tony Curran.
We're at Coopers Chase.
Uh, no, not possible, I'm afraid.
No, we can't come down to the station,
you see.
Ron's quite ill…
and vulnerable these days,
um… incontinent even.
-[whispers] No, don't say that.
-Mm. Mm.
Is it possible
you could send someone over?
-That would be marvelous. Thank you.
-Great. Brilliant. We're on, yeah?
Yes, oh, not quite on, Ron.
You're way too smart.
-All right.
-Scruff up.
Scruff up. Scruff up.
Hm.
[song fades]
Um, I'm going out for the day.
If you need me, just call me.
Oh, no, I'll be fine.
Don't worry about me.
What are you…
[guffawing] What on earth are you wearing?
You look like the Queen.
-Do I?
-[laughing] Yes.
[both laugh]
That was a sad day.
The funeral.
-Do you remember that?
-[Stephen] Of course I do.
September 19th, 2022.
We watched it on the telly.
You were obsessed
with the security arrangements.
Yes, I was.
-[Stephen chuckles]
-[laughs]
Now what are you up to?
Oh, you know, this and that.
I've got a plan.
Oh, my darling Elizabeth.
-You've always got a plan, hm?
-[laughing]
[intriguing music playing]
-[cyclist] Go right.
-[dog yapping]
I like your jumper.
What happens now?
Follow my lead.
This is ever so exciting.
I feel like we're in one
of those Sunday night dramas
about two bright-eyed,
feisty old lady detectives
outsmarting the police at every turn.
Do you feel like that?
-No. And Joyce?
-Yes?
Never use the words "bright-eyed,
feisty old ladies" in my presence again.
Righto.
[indistinct conversation]
[gasping] Young man.
Young man, please help me.
-My… My bag's just been stolen outside--
-Marks and Spencer's.
Yes. Yes, Marks and Spencer's.
It had everything in it. My pension,
all my cash, everything. Please help me.
Oh, yes, of course. Of course.
Uh, let me take your details. Um…
No. No. I want to see
a female police constable.
I promise you I'm fully qualified
and have a very gentle temperament.
-No, it has to be a woman.
-But…
She's a nun!
Yes.
Yes, I'm a nun.
Yes, I've taken vows,
so I can't be with a man, any man.
Except Jesus, of course.
Okay, um…
-Stay here.
-Oh, please hurry.
Okay, okay, yes. Stay here.
[Elizabeth sobs]
A nun, very good.
Wish I'd thought of that. [chuckles]
Now, ladies, how can I…
[mischievous music playing]
…help?
Have you actually
had your bag stolen, Elizabeth?
[scoffing] No.
Good luck to anyone trying
to steal my bag. Can you imagine? [laughs]
Then can I ask
what the two of you are doing here?
I have to go back
to catching criminals and things.
Excellent. Well, first, let me say this.
Stop pretending
you're not pleased to see us again
because I know that you are,
and we're pleased to see you.
This will be so much more fun
if we can all just agree to that.
For the purposes of the tape,
PC De Freitas refuses to answer
but is attempting to hide a slight smile.
[Elizabeth laughs]
Secondly, whatever it is
we're keeping you from,
I know one thing for certain.
It is not catching criminals.
It is something boring.
Uh…
No comment.
We have a question for you.
Oh, go on.
Would you like to be investigating
the murder of Tony Curran?
[tape recorder clicking]
That is never going to happen.
But if we could make it happen,
would you be interested?
Uh… [scoffs]
If we could make it happen?
Who do you think you are, the head of MI5?
No.
No, I'm… I'm just a woman
who doesn't take no for an answer.
As are you, I think.
Well, what's in it for you?
Oh, I do admire your suspicion.
That is a trait I admire above all else.
Oh, good.
Then you won't mind telling me
what's in it for you, then, will you?
Well, we might have the odd question
about the investigation as it goes along.
I-- I can't share anything confidential.
No, no, nothing unprofessional.
I give you my word.
-As a woman of God.
-[snorts]
[inhales sharply]
If I was to say yes
to your help in getting me
on the Tony Curran investigation,
how soon are we talking?
-Give us an hour.
-An hour?
Depending on traffic.
-Our people are in place, waiting.
-She means Ron and Ibrahim.
Here's my contact information.
Text me if you can.
-Interview terminated at 12:47 p.m.
-The tape recorder's off, Joyce.
-Oh, yes, so it is.
-Yes.
All systems go.
Roger that.
[knocking on door]
Good afternoon.
Uh, I'm here to see a Mr. Ron Ritchie.
-Right this way, Inspector.
-Thank you.
[snoring]
Ron? This is the nice policeman.
[shouting] Police!
No, no, no, no, no! No, no, no police!
What do you want from me? Hey?
-I have a right to peaceful protest.
-Easy.
Please excuse Ron's behavior, Inspector.
He's not good around figures of authority.
-Ron. Calm yourself, please.
-Hm? Yeah, okay.
He just wants to talk to you
about the argument you saw
between Ian Ventham and Tony Curran.
I assure you, Mr. Ritchie,
you're not in any trouble.
-I just need to ask you a few questions.
-[Ron shouts] No!
No. I want to speak to the lady copper.
I ain't talking to him.
-Which lady?
-The pretty little lady that came here.
Oh, he means PC De Freitas.
She came to talk to us about window locks.
Ron's got a soft spot for her.
Oh, yes. Oh. [chuckles]
Oh, yeah, well, no,
she's, um, uh, very new.
She's not very experienced, you know?
In fact, she's not on the murder invest--
[Ron yells] I want the lady!
I'll only speak to the lady. Huh!
I'm sorry.
He will only speak to PC De Freit-
Is there any way
you could move her onto your team?
I'll see what I can do.
-[clattering]
-Oh!
-Oh.
-[inspector] Ugh.
Brilliant, Ibsy.
Bloody brilliant, mate. I mean… Oh.
[officer] PC De Freitas.
Just heard from HR.
You're being transferred.
-Where?
-To CID.
Criminal Investigation Department.
You're on the Tony Curran murder
until further notice.
No way.
Really?
-[phone beeping]
-Hm.
[giggles] What does "WTF" mean?
What the fuck?
-Sorry?
-[loudly] What the fuck?
[gasping]
Sorry, dear.
[whispers] My daughter told me.
Sorry about my friend. She's a bit…
-I'm not.
-[chuckles]
[insects chirping]
Hmm.
Whoa, interesting.
[phone beeps]
[keypad tones]
[chuckles]
[screen locking]
Hmm.
Hm.
Joyce, a friend of mine has managed
to get the Coopers Chase accounts.
But, listen, these accounts
are almost impossible to decipher.
-So I was thinking, uh, your daughter, uh…
-Joanna.
-Joanna. She's in finance, right?
-Mm-hmm.
Do you think she could take a look
at them and break them down for us?
In confidence, of course.
I'm not sure. She's terribly busy.
She doesn't even have time to call me.
Just try, okay?
If we're going to investigate this
professionally and efficiently,
we need the full use
of all of our resources.
-I'll see what I can do.
-Good.
Oh.
Joyce, you have a gift.
Hm.
[footsteps receding]
So let me get this straight.
It's a club about murder?
Like a true crime podcast?
Well, in a way.
But we investigate the murders.
[chuckles] Sounds a little macabre.
[chuckling] I must admit,
it does sound a bit bonkers.
But it's a really wonderful group.
We're a team.
So, if you could take a look
at those accounts?
In case you haven't noticed,
I am rather busy, Mum.
Oh, for goodness’ sake, Joanna.
You won't call me more than once a week.
You won't visit me
for more than 47 minutes at a time.
And now you won't even eat my cake.
All I'm asking is, please, set aside
your billionaires for two minutes
and help your only mother out
just this one bloody time!
-I'll see what I can do.
-Thank you.
[Donna] Tony Curran priors.
Reckless driving, common assault,
possession of an illegal weapon.
The list goes on.
Yeah, there's definitely a lot of people
out there who'd want him dead.
But right now, we need to know
who the other man in the photo is.
What photo?
The photo from the Curran murder scene.
There was a few scattered about.
Holiday pics mostly.
Family weddings and so on.
But this was of him
and another man which we can't identify.
It's just come back from forensics.
Would you… like to take a look?
Oh, yes, please.
Sorry.
Is it not cool to say
"yes, please" in CID?
I'm really not the person
to ask about what's cool.
Just, uh, take a look
at the photo, De Freitas.
You can call me Donna.
Feel a bit weird otherwise.
Donna?
Yes, my name.
My first name.
Yeah, I mean, I'll try. But… [laughing]
I'm not really a first name kind of guy.
I don't think I even know
what Griffiths' first name is,
and he's been with us for seven years.
[Donna] And you don't know
who this is next to Curran?
No, Griffiths is, uh… He's working on it.
You can tell Griffiths to stop working
on it 'cause that's Bobby Tanner.
What?
Major crime kingpin.
Gave the Met police a runaround.
They've been looking for him for years.
He turns up here.
[titters] Irony.
-Wh-- So the Met never found him?
-No. And I'll tell you something else.
There's a third man,
but he's been mostly cropped out.
What?
Yeah, look.
See his arm reflected
in the mirror behind them?
-Oh, yeah.
-[rustling]
Well spotted.
I'll let Griffiths know.
[Elizabeth] Hot as possible, Joyce.
They're here. Ready?
-Ready.
-Now, remember.
-Scooch over.
Any info we get out of them
will be a bonus.
Right.
Hudson will be tight-lipped, no doubt.
So we have to make him feel uncomfortable,
as uncomfortable as possible.
In my experience, people are
more likely to crack or reveal things
when they're uncomfortable.
I think you get more information
out of people with kindness and cake.
-[Ron laughs]
-[Elizabeth] Yes.
And have you ever had
to interrogate an enemy spy
in former East Germany, Joyce?
-Well, no.
-[phone ringing]
Hello, Joanna, darling.
[Joanna] So,
I looked into Ian Ventham's accounts.
[Ron] There they go.
[Joanna] Turns out
there's some pretty spicy stuff in there.
I've sent you the PDFs.
Do you know what a PDF is?
Take a wild guess, Jo.
Ibrahim does.
He's well in with everything.
-[Ron] Uh… [laughing]
-PDF.
-[clearing throat]
-Oh, bingo.
-[intriguing music playing]
-[gasps]
My goodness.
Oh.
[chuckling] Oh.
Oh, goodness indeed, Joyce.
What a clever daughter you somehow have.
This is crucial information.
Now we have some real leverage.
-Well done, Jo.
-Ah, brilliant.
-[Joanna] Thanks. Gotta run.
-[doorbell rings]
-Here we go. Here we go.
-[knocking on door]
-Please come in.
-Thank you. [exhales]
[clearing throat]
[door closing]
Good afternoon. I, uh…
I believe you've all met PC De Freitas.
She and I are investigating
the murder of Tony Curran.
Uh, now, I'm told
that you all have some knowledge of…
Mr. Curran as he was preparing
to redevelop the--
We've forgotten our manners,
Detective Chief Inspector.
Please do sit down.
-Come sit down.
-Oh. Oh.
Take the weight off. There you go.
[chuckling] Make yourself comfortable.
[chuckles]
[sighing] Ooh.
Is it me or is it hot in here?
Of course it's hot in here.
I'm a 76-year-old woman.
[exhales]
That is a firm grip you got there,
Mr. Ritchie.
I thought
you were very ill and vulnerable.
Oh, good days and bad days
at this age, DCI Hudson.
You know? Good days and bad.
And your missing tooth seems
to have grown back.
What's that?
Oh yeah, look at that. It's a miracle. Ha!
Oh, how rude of us.
We haven't offered you any tea.
Um, do you like sugar?
Oh, no, no. I'm trying to cut down.
But you must have cake.
Are you allowed cake on duty?
I do hope so.
No, I've had rather
a large lunch. [chuckles]
Go on, then. Why not, eh?
-[laughing] Here you go now. Tuck in.
-[laughs] Oh, look at that.
[clears throat] Sorry, I can't, um… It's…
[Ron] Steady.
-Oh, God, that's good.
-Oh.
-Isn't it?
-Oh!
So, Ron,
um, you observed Ian and Tony
having a row in the car park.
-Right? That's why we're here.
-Yeah. Oh, yeah. It was a proper bust-up.
You know, it ended badly.
Tony stormed off, uh…
[exhaling deeply]
We reckon it was about money.
The love of which, they say,
is the root of all evil.
Although wasn't it Jung who said--
Now, my son, he told me that Tony's house
had an excellent security system.
Oh, yes? Did your son know Tony Curran?
[inhales] Well,
only in the sense that we all did.
I mean,
he was quite a local character, Tony.
Yes, he was a real man about town.
Yeah, I mean, we all… we all had dealings
with him at some stage or another.
No big deal.
It'd still be, you know,
useful to talk to your son.
It's Jason, isn't it?
Yeah, sure, no probs. No probs.
He's going to come round and see me.
You know? I mean, I doubt he can help.
Well, yeah, probably best
to let the police do their work, and--
I think what Ron's trying to say is maybe
the security system gave you something.
It was on the blink.
Waste of money, if you ask me.
Well, it's odd, isn't it, that a builder
should have a defective security system?
Yes, what about the time of death?
Uh, we couldn't possibly say.
You know, it's not,
uh, public information right now.
Too sensitive to release it.
You're quite right. And… [exhales]
…this meeting's been all give and no take.
I mean, I, for example, happen to know
that there were three original investors
in Coopers Chase
when it was first being developed.
There was Ian Ventham, Tony Curran,
and an anonymous investor
under a shell account
called "Bloomin' Marvelous."
Did you know that?
-No, I didn't know that, no.
-[Elizabeth] Ah.
I also have this.
A very old phone?
It may be old, but it still works.
And it contains PDFs of detailed
financial accounts of Ian Ventham,
which show that
Tony Curran's stake in this land
reverts to Ian Ventham if he dies,
which means that Ian Ventham
made millions from this murder.
Right.
In exchange for time of death.
I'm afraid I cannot divulge
that information.
[sighs]
Do you want the files or not?
11:24.
-PC De Freitas.
-That's pretty precise.
He had a smartwatch
that recorded when his heartbeat stopped.
PC De Freitas!
Do you want the files or not?
-[DCI Hudson hesitating]
-Here you go.
[inhales sharply]
[exhales]
[DCI Hudson] Thank you.
Hm.
[breathes deeply]
Where the hell did you get
Ian Ventham's accounts from anyway?
I mean, it's a private company.
Even we couldn't get 'em.
Teamwork.
[chuckling]
People of our generation still remember
how valuable that can be.
However did you get
that puff pastry so light?
Well, the trick is you've gotta work it
really fast while it's still cold.
-Here you go.
-You must be so good with your hands.
-I've been told that a few times.
-[Ron] Jason! Ah!
-There he is. My son, Jason.
-All right, Dad.
As promised. There you go now.
DCI Hudson. Jason.
Jason "The Hammer" Ritchie.
Oh, no introduction needed there.
[laughs] I've seen all your fights.
Shame it had to end, eh?
The injury and all.
-Yeah, well, these things happen.
-Sorry, yeah.
-Still, the… the TV work's exciting, eh?
-Yeah.
Aren't you in a Snow White panto
this Christmas?
I am. I'm playing the prince.
DCI Hudson,
what about a quick photograph of our
three-time WBA middleweight champion?
-Right here, right now. Jump in.
-Oh, thanks very much. You sure?
Oh yeah. Of course he's sure. Yeah.
They're gonna love this
down at the station.
All right, pucker up, lick your lips.
-I can't believe it's you.
-It's me.
-Fists up.
-[Ron] There you go.
[DCI Hudson] Take a few.
-[Ron] That's it. Looking good.
-[DCI Hudson] Ding ding.
-Very natural.
-[DCI Hudson] Wallop out.
I love it. Right on the button.
-Got it?
-[Ron] You're gonna like those.
-One of those was a good one. Yeah.
-Oh, look at that. [laughing]
-Thanks, mate.
-No problem. I've gotta go.
-Yeah. Just a sec. Uh…
-Okay.
What's your thinking
about Tony Curran and Ian Ventham?
-Uh, you knew them a bit, right?
-No.
I mean, I knew of 'em.
[inhales] Tony had plenty of enemies,
and so does Ian.
Any come to mind?
No.
Not right now.
Anyway, I've gotta go.
-Okay. All right.
-Well, ju-- Call me if something does.
-DCI Hudson, good to meet you.
-Yeah. And you.
-All right, PC De Freitas, all the best.
-Yes.
Here you go. Wait up.
Wait up. Wait up, Jason!
DCI Hudson, I know you like cake.
I want to give you the rest
of the coffee and walnut.
You should probably let Donna drive.
There's an awful lot of rum in that.
Really makes the walnuts pop, I find.
-Ah. Thank you.
-Good to see you.
[Elizabeth] Maud.
-What are you after, Elizabeth?
-[Elizabeth] Oh.
I just wanted to say
I'm so sorry for your loss.
Tony was a bloody good bloke.
Do you have any idea who killed him?
I've got lots of ideas
about lots of things, love.
But it don't mean I'm sharing 'em,
and not with them coppers around.
Ugh. Yes, what a lot of wankers.
-But then police usually are, aren't they?
-Yeah.
[both laughing]
[Elizabeth] Oh, what lovely flowers.
Yes, they're from an old friend
who loved Tony too.
Some people still have manners.
Mm.
[sniffing] Mmm.
Jason, are you okay, son?
Hey, I thought you were coming for a pint.
-Yeah, I've gotta go. Something came up.
-Oh, come on. You just got here.
-Well, Dad, I have to leave.
-Jason, what is it? What's wrong?
-Dad, just leave it, yeah?
-Hey, why are you so pissed off? Hm?
Okay, all right. Look, I know
that you're embarrassed about the TV work.
You just don't have to make it
so bloody obvious.
What? I'm not embarrassed, Jason.
I mean, I won't lie. I…
I understand the boxing world much better.
My God, you were a contender, son.
There you go.
You just can't help yourself, can you?
What?
No, I've gotta go.
-All right. Just be careful.
-Right now.
-[engine revs]
-Just be careful on the bike.
[curious music playing]
Jason lied to you.
Eh?
It's in Tony Curran's file.
Jason used to work for him
and Ian Ventham doing odd jobs
just before he got all that TV work.
-And I'll tell you something else.
-What?
Jason is the third man in that photo
from the crime scene.
He's the arm in the mirror.
It's the same tattoo. Where's your phone?
It's… here.
Now, go on, show me.
Look.
[exhales sharply]
-Jason seemed in a rush to get away too.
-That he did.
Yeah. We should keep an eye on him
and Ian Ventham.
Mmm.
Don't want people disappearing on us.
[horn blaring]
-[horn honking]
-[Elizabeth scoffing]
You just got overtaken by a learner.
For God's sake, Ibrahim,
we're trying to find out how fast
Ian Ventham could have driven
from Coopers Chase to Tony Curran's house.
Key word, "fast."
-Anyone want a Jelly Baby?
-Mm.
My calculations are not based on speed.
I have this rather complex algorithm
which will enable me to determine
if Ian Ventham could have got there
in time to murder Tony Curran.
-Uh, just be patient.
-Hm.
[Ian] Yeah, look,
I'm incredibly busy today, you understand?
My business partner dying,
a lot for me to handle.
Of course. Uh, would you like to tell me
who that is with Tony?
-That's Bobby Tanner.
-Correct, Bobby Tanner.
Police have been looking
for him for years.
List of allegations as long as your arm.
Name turns up all over the place,
I'm… told.
Yeah, well, I thought he was dead.
Where'd you get this?
It was at the crime scene.
Was it?
Okay, all right.
Why would you get mixed up
with Bobby Tanner, Ian?
He's a nasty piece of work.
Cuts his enemies' fingers off,
sends it back in the post.
We got a freezer full of them
in Scotland Yard.
You might as well tell us now,
or we'll find out another way.
He's the third owner. [exhales]
The third owner of what?
Coopers Chase. Keep up.
Jesus, you lot are slow.
Tony Curran brought him on
for a cash boost to finish the job.
-Listen, it wasn't my idea.
-Do you know where he might be?
Aren't you listening?
I thought he was dead.
He's been missing now… oh, God, for years.
If he is alive,
you wanna get on with finding him.
He's a dangerous man.
You think Bobby Tanner killed Tony Curran?
I dunno. That's your job, isn't it?
Look, I've got to get on.
Why did you argue with Tony Curran
just before he died?
Just business. Bit complicated to explain.
Jason Ritchie's in that photo too.
Tattoo is a giveaway.
Did you ask him to kill Curran for you?
I wouldn't piss on Jason Ritchie
if he was on fire.
Be nice if both your partners
were dead, wouldn't it?
You stood to gain over 12 million quid
with Tony out the picture.
How the hell do you know about that?
Look, I didn't kill Tony Curran,
if that's what you're thinking.
No, no, I…
I was with investors all morning.
Concentrate on finding Bobby Tanner
and putting him in a cell.
Safest place for him, for all of us.
You seem very worried all of a sudden,
Mr. Ventham.
Yeah, you're sweating.
Yeah, okay, whatever.
I have an urgent appointment.
You do your job, if you still know how.
Let me do mine, huh?
[slurping] Mm. I've gotta go. [sighs]
-Yeah, we'll talk again soon.
-[Ian] Yeah.
Where's Mrs. Ventham?
You'll have to ask her lawyer.
[Donna] Mm.
Divorces are bloody expensive,
aren't they?
-[birds chirping]
-[dog barking]
Oh, yes, I think my algorithm
worked quite well,
allowing for traffic
and given my 18-mile--
Ibrahim!
Could Ian Ventham have got here in time
to kill Tony Curran, yes or no?
No.
-Oh. Bugger.
-[sighing]
-Bugger.
Bugger.
[keyboards clacking]
Hey.
Sir?
Ian Ventham couldn't have murdered
Tony Curran.
What?
And why not?
He couldn't have driven there in time.
He would've gotten there
seven minutes after the death.
Uh, and you've learned this news from…
The Thursday Murder Club.
I'm sorry, the what now?
Well, that's what they call themselves.
You know, Elizabeth and the gang.
They drove to Curran's house this morning,
and they figured it out.
I've got Griffiths out there
doing that exact exercise right now.
[laughing] I mean, bloody hell.
I've been in this job for nearly 30 years.
I'm not gonna be pushed around
by four pensioners. Ah!
-Griffiths, good. What's the news?
-Well, based on our findings…
Oh, look, just tell me.
Could Ventham have got there in time
to kill Curran, yes or no?
-No.
-Right, piss off, Griffiths.
[door closing]
[phone ringing]
-Hello, Donna.
-[Donna on phone] Elizabeth, hi.
-I need your help.
-Yes?
At Tony Curran's crime scene, we found
a photo of Curran with Bobby Tanner.
Bobby Tanner?
I've heard of him.
He's a nasty piece of work.
Mixed up in drugs and murder.
Right.
And… we need to talk to him,
but he's been missing for years,
and I was hoping
that you could help us find him.
-[ominous music playing]
-Yes, of course.
In return for any recent information
you might have.
[Donna] Elizabeth.
Come on, Donna.
You know how these things work.
[exhales]
You know the photo I told you about?
There's another man in it.
Mm-hmm. Who?
Jason Ritchie.
What?
And there's more.
Call me back in a few minutes.
[ominous music intensifies]
[panting]
[sighs and chuckles]
[gasps]
Don't wake the dead.
Good God.
-Did you see his face?
-Too dark.
[crickets chirping]
So, even if Ian Ventham's no longer
the prime suspect,
that doesn't mean that he didn't get
somebody else to kill him.
Exactly. And that's where it gets awkward.
The police are planning
on talking with Jason.
Rumor has it
that he used to do the odd one-off job
for Mr. Ventham and Tony Curran
when they needed a bit of extra muscle.
-How odd?
-That's what we're trying to establish.
I haven't told Ron.
Thankfully, he's preoccupied
with organizing the protest.
Oh, and on that note,
I'd better get going.
Shall I pick you up on Monday?
We can go to the protest together.
Wouldn't miss it.
They cannot be allowed
to dig up that cemetery
and throw Penny into the street.
It simply cannot happen.
No.
But on Monday, we shall fight.
["Power to the People"
by John Lennon playing]
Everybody! Everybody, gather round now!
We're gonna form a human barricade
in front of the cemetery,
and we're gonna be in solidarity
with each other. Are we not?
-[cheering]
-Yes!
Let's do this now.
Here you go.
Stay strong.
[laughs]
Let's not live on our knees, Ron.
-I agree, Elizabeth.
-We will never surrender.
Thank you, John.
Thank you for coming, both of you.
-Let's stop him.
-Uh-huh. Oh, look at you. Well done, lads.
Bernard's recycled an old slogan.
Mine's original.
Well, listen, no argy-bargy
between the two of you, okay?
-Solidarity rules the day.
-Absolutely.
[laughs] Top man, Ibsy. Top man.
Joyce, what are you doing
bringing in a coffee machine?
This isn't a village fete.
This is serious business.
Yes, of course, but good coffee
means we can protest longer.
-Oh! Such a wise woman. Yeah.
-[engines revving]
The enemy approaches!
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Come on! They can't do that!
Get a shovel.
Take the back gate. Start digging.
I'm not going to make
much progress with one shovel.
Legally, work needs to start today, yes?
So all you need to do is break ground.
Get out.
Okay. Okay.
[protestors clamoring]
[horn blaring]
Get out of the way!
[horn continues blaring]
[Ron] Over there.
Off you go. Coming through.
My God, it's like The Walking Dead.
[horn honking]
Go on. Coming through. Hold your ground.
Yeah, hold steady. That's it.
All right.
-What the hell's going on?
-[booing]
What's this? Reliving the '80s, are you?
Remembering the days
you last got it up, yeah?
-What do you think's going on? A protest!
-[cheering]
There are people here
who've seen off better men than you.
We've got teachers and soldiers,
doctors and bankers.
-[protestors agreeing]
-And what do we want?
-No digging!
-Larger font on the menu.
-Fully nude models for the art class.
-[man] Yes.
Wait, wait, wait. We can't all just shout
random things we want. No!
Solidarity!
Okay, everyone out of the way.
Let us start digging, yeah?
-You're not entering this cemetery.
-No, no, no.
Get your hands off him, Ventham.
Piss off, Jason, you backstabbing prick.
I'm onto you, mate.
Oh, are you? You'll have to get through me
and the rest of this crowd to get in here.
[laughing] So, uh… Ian Ventham out.
[chanting] Ian Ventham out!
-Ian Ventham out! That's it!
-Ian Ventham out! Ian Ventham out!
-[Ron] Come on now! Solidarity.
-[chanting continues]
-[mysterious music playing]
[Ron] Stay together, brothers and sisters.
Raise your voices up.
-Ian Ventham out!
-All right. I'm calling the police.
Do it. Tell 'em you assaulted a vicar.
Ian Ventham out!
[chanting continues]
Hello. Um…
Did you… did you see a woodpecker?
I thought I saw a woodpecker.
No.
Oh, I've seen you fixing things
around the place, haven't I?
Um, Bogdan, is it?
[breathing heavily] Yeah.
I'm Marina.
[chuckles softly]
This is also my mother's name.
-No!
-Mm.
-Really?
-[chuckles]
Well, that's a coincidence, isn't it?
Well, it is a lovely name.
Of course, I would say so, wouldn't I?
[chuckles]
Is she here with you?
-No. No. She's in, uh, Poland still.
-Ah.
[speaking Polish]
I am sure you miss her, hm?
And she misses you.
[sighs]
[speaking Polish]
I miss her… every single day.
Hmm.
-[speaking English] You speak Polish?
-Yeah, a little bit. [chuckles]
She is the reason I came to England.
You know,
there is, uh, better work here, more pay,
so long as I can send money home.
Where in Poland are you from?
Kraków.
Oh, I had the most wonderful soup
in Kraków. Uh, Krupnik.
Ah, it's the… the barley soup.
-Yeah.
-[laughs]
What were you doing in Poland?
Traveling circus.
[laughs] Those were the days.
Okay.
[exhales sharply]
Ridiculous, no?
Do all this with one shovel,
but it's my responsibility now.
Oh, you've taken over
from Tony as the boss?
Yes, I am the, uh, primary contractor
for Ian now.
Oh.
Did Ian give you that job
before Tony died?
Yes, Marina, it was my job
before Tony died. Why?
Are you wishing to ask me something?
Well, it's just that we know
Ian gained a lot from Tony's death,
so I was wondering if he, well…
he asked someone to kill Tony for him?
I don't know.
Maybe.
Well, then let me be more specific.
Did Ian ask you to kill Tony for him?
No.
And even if he did ask, I'd still say no.
I will do many things for Ian Ventham.
I will dig up old bones,
but I will never kill a man for him.
Hm?
[protestors clamoring]
[Jason] No one wants you here, Ian,
so why don't you go home?
Yeah? Just read the signs and get going.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey! Hands off me. Stop.
Hands off! Off, off, off! Oi!
-Hands off me! Stop it!
-[indistinct yelling]
Don't touch me! Get off! Oi!
-No one wants you!
-All right!
-Why don't you listen to us?
-Hey!
-Oi!
-Why don't you?
[protestors murmuring]
No! This…
[panting]
This… [exhales]
[protestors gasp]
Let me through. Let me through.
[indistinct whispering]
[shutter clicking]
[breathing shakily]
He's dead.
-[protestors gasping, murmuring]
-Hm.
Bloody hell.
So,
we're all witnesses to a murder.
[clears throat] First question, then.
Uh, how do you know
it was a murder and not a heart attack?
-I mean, he was very stressed.
-Yes.
The probable cause of death
was an overdose of fentanyl
administered just before he died.
They're waiting
for the full lab results now.
Where did you get your information from?
Donna texted me.
-She's being very helpful indeed.
-Where did this fentanyl come from?
Medical professionals use it
in anesthesia and pain relief.
Very effective on lots of things.
But a high dose can be absolutely fatal.
So it had to be someone who had access
to needles and drugs, right?
Yes, well, that means almost everybody
at Coopers Chase, Ron.
So I've collected photos
from everyone at the scene.
My guess is it happened during the scrum.
A lethal dose administered quietly
and coolly while everyone was fighting.
-So the killer is in these pictures?
-Absolutely.
We're all in these pictures.
We're all suspects.
[ominous music playing]
Speaking of pictures, we haven't solved
the Bobby Tanner conundrum yet.
What's that?
-Who?
-What?
-Oh, sorry, didn't I mention it to you?
-No, you didn't.
No, Donna also told me that they found
a photo at Tony Curran's murder scene
of Tony Curran, a notorious criminal
called Bobby Tanner, and Ja--
And who?
It doesn't matter. Uh… No.
-It doesn't matter--
-No, no, no.
You… You shouldn't be keeping things
from us. Elizabeth, we're a team.
No, no. I'm not. I'm not. I just…
You see, Donna texts me
late at night sometimes.
I was just waiting for the right time
to tell you, that's all.
Well, now would appear
to be the perfect time.
Would you care to fill us in?
At the moment,
it's Bobby Tanner the police
are looking for, and so should we.
Bobby Tanner is the third owner
of Coopers Chase
with Ian Ventham and Tony Curran.
And it explicitly states
in Ian Ventham's will
that the development of Coopers Chase
will continue after Ian's death.
Only Bobby Tanner can stop it.
And no one can find him.
So the battle
for our homes is not over yet.
Hm. Dead or alive,
Ian Ventham can still screw us.
So this Bobby Tanner is the sole
surviving owner of Coopers Chase?
Yes. Yes, it seems so.
But he may be dead too. No one knows.
So if we found him,
we could stop the development, right?
And save Coopers Chase?
And the destruction of the cemetery?
Yes. So we better get started.
Yes, intermediate knitting starts
here in one hour.
[Elizabeth] Okay.
[Stephen] When did you start playing?
[Bogdan] My father taught me
when I was ten,
and I didn't beat him till I was 13.
[Stephen and Bogdan laugh]
-[Bogdan] He wouldn't let me win.
-[Stephen] That's remarkable.
-Yes.
-[Bogdan] Checkmate.
[Stephen] Oh, good heavens. Ah, Elizabeth.
This gentleman came to see you.
-And he also plays chess.
-[Bogdan chuckles]
-He really is a remarkable player.
-Mm.
-Oh, and he fixed the Wi-Fi in my study.
Bogdan, what an unexpected surprise.
Sorry to intrude, Elizabeth.
Not at all. Welcome.
Ah. Thank you for the game, Stephen.
I must go.
-It was my pleasure.
-[Bogdan] I must be off.
I'll see him out.
-[Bogdan] Elizabeth.
-[Elizabeth] So what are you doing here?
[Bogdan] We need to talk.
I didn't know who else to go to.
Police asked me where I was when Ian died.
I told them, "In cemetery with Marina."
But they can't find any Marina
at Coopers Chase.
So I have to ask around for the pushy lady
who asks too many questions.
And everyone knew it was you.
All right. You got me.
I wanted to speak with you,
and I thought using that name
might be a way of gaining your trust.
Hm, it was a cheap trick.
It was. It's a force of habit.
Sorry about that.
[speaking Polish] So why are you here?
I have something to show you.
Tonight.
After dark.
Meet me in the cemetery. Come alone.
[in English] Completely alone.
Please.
[whispers] Completely alone.
Thank you.
[footsteps receding]
-["LoveDrug" by Lady Gaga playing]
-Watch out. Twirl, position. Chest out.
Left and right.
Hold, hold, hold, hold, hold.
Last twirl. Up, left. Great, good job.
♪ Of your lovedrug
I don't wanna… ♪
There he is.
♪ I don't wanna cry… ♪
Present.
-And present.
-Perfect.
♪ Until I feel all right
I just need… ♪
So, uh, what's all this about, then, eh?
I've already told you what I know,
which is nothing.
I was at the gym
with my mate Dan Fairhurst when Tony died.
You were with him before Curran died
but not when Curran died.
-Do you see the difference?
-Yeah, well…
The cleaning lady found him.
Maybe she did it.
[DCI Hudson] You know, I see it like this.
A murderer is not the first person
to see the victim dead,
but the last person to see them alive.
-Nice.
-Old episode of Columbo.
So what's going on, then?
What are you two accusing me of?
Why did Ian Ventham call you three times
directly after his row with Tony Curran?
Was he asking you a favor?
Did Ventham ask you to kill Tony Curran
because he was afraid of him?
No. No, it was about, uh, something else.
I don't think it was, Jason.
There were other things going on.
Yes, there certainly was.
Ventham paid some
of your old gambling debts, right?
And because Ventham paid your debts,
you would do
the occasional odd job for him.
-Anything he asked--
-No. No. Not anything he asked.
Why did he call you, Jason?
Just…
Just stuff. All right, look…
-I've really gotta get back to rehearsals.
-Do you know Bobby Tanner, Jason?
-What? Bobby Tanner?
-[unsettling music playing]
He's dead, isn't he?
Do you remember this photo being taken?
No.
Well… that's your arm in the mirror. No?
You're up to your neck
in organized crime, aren't you, Jason?
What's one more little execution, eh?
Why were you in such a hurry
the other day?
-Were you trying to run away?
-I really do not have time for this.
Jason Ritchie,
I'm placing you under arrest
on the suspicion of murder of Tony Curran.
What are you talking about?
You don't have any evidence.
You won't answer our questions.
You have no alibi.
You have means and motive.
And on top of all that, I've got a concern
that you're gonna vanish on us.
In short, you're a flight risk.
So, yes, we can take you into custody.
-Wanna pop those skates down for me?
-[grunting]
[whispering] Oh, shit.
The Tony Curran, Ian Ventham murder.
I mean, surely it must be the same killer.
I mean, here we have two business partners
murdered within days of each other.
So, someone who wants
to stop the redevelopment.
What about Bernard?
He was pretty agitated at the protest.
Yeah. Bad-tempered, that one.
He's also a chemist, which makes him
the most likely to have access to a toxin.
-I'll mark him a nine.
-No, that's too high. No, give him a six.
[sighs] Fine. I'll give him a seven.
[Ron] All right, fair play.
What about Father Mackie?
Angriest person at the protest.
-I'd say he's our first ten.
-He's been acting very strange lately.
And no one would suspect a priest.
-You want a top-up?
-Yes.
[Ron exhales]
You know, I've been thinking.
With Tony and Ian gone,
do you think that changes things?
I mean, do you think
they'll kick us out on our arses?
Depends what happens
to Coopers Chase Investments, doesn't it?
-If they can't find this Bobby Tanner.
-Yeah, that's right.
-Oh, no, no. No, not the book.
-Oh, sorry.
Thank you.
[sighs]
I would miss it here.
Yeah.
Here, if you choose to be alone,
you close your door.
Hmm.
If you prefer to be with people,
you open it.
What better recipe for happiness?
Reminds me of my old college at Oxford,
only with better food, less snobbery.
-Aw! [scoffs]
-[phone ringing]
-Oh. Here we go. Hello?
-[ringing continues]
-Uh-- Hello? H-- Oh, sorry about this.
-Mm.
[groaning]
[ringing stops]
-Hello? Yep.
-[Jason speaks indistinctly]
-What?
-[Jason] I've just been arrested.
All right.
All right. Listen, don't say a word, okay?
Keep your mouth shut.
We'll sort this out, all right? Shtum.
Say nothing. Okay? All right, bye.
-[clicking]
-[somber music playing]
That was Jason.
He's just been arrested
for the murder of Tony Curran.
Oh, Ron.
Oh, bloody hell.
-[Elizabeth] This way?
-[Bogdan] Yeah, through here.
Your husband Stephen is not well, is he?
No. No, he's not.
[somber music continues]
You put something in his tea?
Yes.
To help him sleep, a pill.
Just one though. Any more might be lethal.
It was very nice of you to come over
and play chess with him, you know?
That's the first time in a long time
that Stephen's played chess
with anyone else.
Ah, he's good player.
-Tough for me.
-Will you come and do it again?
I would love that very much, yeah.
[chuckles] I don't have many friends here.
I should warn you, though,
that Stephen has good days and bad days.
-You got him on a good day.
-My mother is the same, hm?
She don't always… remember me.
She is very sick.
I don't know how much longer I…
Oh, Bogdan, I'm so sorry.
You should go and see her.
[clears throat]
I would love to see her,
you know, just once more, but I can't.
Why not?
[inhales deeply]
All of us workers, when we come here,
they take our passports when we arrive
for, uh, for safekeeping.
It's normal in this work, they said.
And who are "they"?
It's all right. I'll… I'll fix it somehow.
[sniffles]
Anyway, here we are.
[mysterious music playing]
So you find human remains in a grave.
Why would I find that mysterious?
Because, Elizabeth,
those bones were put on top of coffin.
Hm?
Oh.
And why would someone dig up a grave
to put bones on top of bones?
To hide a body.
I think we have another murder
on our hands.
[siren wailing]
[man speaking indistinctly over radio]
Lift up.
[indistinct chatter]
-And that's what Elizabeth told you?
-More or less, yes.
[inhales deeply]
Right, come with me.
[vehicle doors closing]
Knock, knock.
-May we come in?
-[Ron] Looks like you're already here.
Come for more cake, Inspector?
Elizabeth, no more games, please.
This is serious.
Oh.
I'd like to know
just exactly how you found this body.
-I have already explained this to Donna.
-Well, I want to hear it from you.
Oh, yes, of course.
Well, um, you see, I was out for a walk.
Um, I was looking for narcissi.
Narcissi?
-Oh. Daffodil bulbs for my window box.
-Your window box?
Yes, for spring color,
you know, next year.
-Right, yeah.
-Yes.
-And, um, I was digging around--
-Oh, with your hands?
No, not with my hands.
Don't be ridiculous. I had a trowel.
-[laughing] Oh, silly me, a trowel.
-Yes, a trowel for the bulbs.
-Of course.
-And that was when I found the bones. It…
It was such a shock. It really was
the most remarkable coincidence.
[inhales deeply]
I'm losing my patience with you
and your… band of merry pensioners.
Listen, mate,
you've got my son sitting in a cell.
And as of right now,
all your evidence is circumstantial.
I'm sorry, pal, but that's not enough
to charge someone with murder.
So why don't you drop the hard-man act
and get out there
and find the real killer?
Oh, I'd bloody love
to find the real killer, Ron.
-Good.
-I would bloody love to.
So if you and your "Tuesday Death Society"
can leave this case alone
for five minutes,
maybe we can make some actual progress.
You know, I suggest you lot stick to,
uh, Rotary Club dinners, golfing,
feeding those weird llamas out there,
and taking your statins,
and leave the rest to us, hm,
the professionals.
So for the hard of hearing,
let's turn up
those hearing aids loud and clear.
Police work is off-limits
to anyone who isn't the police.
You got it?
Yeah, got it.
Right.
Thank you for your time.
De Freitas.
[footsteps receding]
I'd run a check
on those bones if I were you.
-Could be significant.
-[whispers] Okay.
[footsteps receding]
[ominous music playing]
-[door handle turning]
-[inhales sharply]
-[door creaking]
-Hm?
[floorboards creaking]
[footsteps approaching]
[footsteps running]
[dog barking]
[scoffs]
[inhales sharply]
[ominous music continues]
-Hey.
-Hm?
Oh, hello.
[panting] Look,
I shouldn't really be talking to you, but…
I wanted to tell you
that the bones we found in the cemetery,
they belonged to a man
called Peter Mercer.
[whispers] What?
Oh my God, that's extraordinary.
[ominous music fades]
Constable De Freitas,
meet Detective Inspector Penny Gray
and her husband, John.
-Hello. Nice to meet you.
-Hi.
-You should have seen her in her day.
-She was a spectacle to behold.
It's an honor, ma'am.
Penny, Donna here
is a brilliant young police officer.
[chuckles]
She very kindly filled me in
on the bones that Bogdan dug up.
They belonged to a man named Peter Mercer,
who has a metal plate in the knee,
but then they'd been buried
for 50 years or more, so…
So nothing to tie them in
with Ventham's murder?
No, but Ron and Ibrahim
interviewed several residents,
and they've been able
to successfully eliminate Bernard,
Marjorie, and Father Mackie
from the suspect list.
Ah, is that so?
Oh. Do you know, back in the '70s,
Penny and I used to come
to church services here.
Did you?
Mackie was different then though.
Calmer, you might say.
Well, well done, Donna.
You hear that, Penny?
Your legacy continues
with this young woman.
[uplifting music playing]
So, you have no recollection
of this photo ever being taken?
Look, I've told you,
people take photos of me all the time.
Like you did.
I… I don't know what this is about.
-I'll tell you what--
-Sir, I'm sorry. I tried to stop him.
-[DCI Hudson] No, not… Ron?
-Thank you.
-Dad?
-[DCI Hudson] What are you doing here?
What the hell are you wearing?
[laughs] Did you get married in that suit?
I did, mate, yeah.
Twice, in fact.
Now, Jason is entitled
to legal representation,
and I'm here to provide it.
You're not a lawyer, Ron.
Well, I may not be qualified,
but I have the necessary training.
I've represented myself against your lot
for many a day in the year now.
Oh my God.
You're holding
an innocent man here, Hudson,
and all your evidence
is circumstantial at best. Hmm?
He has no alibi, Ron.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Ibrahim!
Jason's new lawyer has asked me
to be present
for his son's psychiatric evaluation.
You see?
-He's suffering from heavy distress…
-Eh?
…clear signs of PTSD.
If you continue without me,
you leave yourselves open
to a negligence case.
-DCI Hudson, I know you like cake.
-[DCI Hudson] No, no!
I've made my special lemon drizzle.
You've all got important work to do here.
Must keep your energy up.
Shall I cut a slice for everyone?
Everybody, out of my office,
or I'll have you all arrested!
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Last time I looked,
this was the United Kingdom.
And in the United Kingdom,
a man has a right to a lawyer.
Jason had three phone conversations
with Ian Ventham
shortly before Tony Curran's murder.
He's a kid! They're always on their phone.
And where was Jason
when Curran was murdered?
He's refusing to tell us,
which tells me, Ron, is that he's guilty.
[exhales]
Well?
Well, what?
Well, where were you?
That's none of your business,
and you're supposed to be my lawyer.
Well, right now I'm your dad.
So stop all this nonsense and tell us all,
where were you when Curran was murdered?
Then we can get home
in time to see the West Ham match.
Come on, now. Go on.
[sighs]
I was with Ian Ventham's wife.
Gemma Ventham?
-We were…
-Having an affair?
-Oh, Jason.
-Hm.
And she'll confirm this?
Yeah. Yeah, look, I'm sorry, Dad.
No harm, son.
[titters] That's how I met your mum.
Well, there you go, me ol' cocker.
There's your alibi.
Can you prove it?
Yeah. Yeah, I can, actually.
Can I have my phone?
Ooh.
[inhales deeply]
It's time-stamped and dated. You can check
with Gemma as well, if you must.
[Ron laughs] Well, DCI Hudson,
there you have it.
No reason to hold an innocent man.
I suggest you go look
for the real murderer now.
-[phone thuds on desk]
-Out.
[chuckles]
-All of you, out of my office right now.
-I'll leave the cake.
-Out!
-Ah-- Mm.
-Dad, you're a legend.
-Pleasure, son. Pleasure. Ibs…
-You too, De Freitas.
-Yeah.
[phone chiming]
[tires screeching]
[indistinct yelling]
-I didn't know you had a car.
-It was a retirement gift.
-Oh.
-From MI6.
[indistinct chatter]
You really think
that Bobby Tanner is here?
We've been searching for him for years.
Yeah, well, I'm as sure as I can be,
but I like to work off a hunch,
you know, take a risk.
Sometimes it pays off,
as you'll find out, more and more.
-How did you figure it out?
-A few days ago, I was sent some flowers.
They were lilies, hyacinths,
carnations, tulips, and ranunculus.
-Oh, sounds nice.
-Yeah.
Very nice, except they came with a card,
and on the card was written, "Back off."
And those flowers together are the most
toxic arrangement a person could get.
That was a clear warning.
Wait, you think this is linked
to the investors' account
at Coopers Chase?
-[bell tolling]
-Donna, you read my mind.
The flowers I was sent were fresh
and hand-delivered,
which means they came
from close to Coopers Chase.
-And then I remembered the card.
-Card?
The card on Maud's flowers, in memoriam
to Tony Curran, was signed "B.T.,"
and the design on the card
matched my card exactly.
[mysterious music playing]
It's very distinctive.
I did an online search.
Thorny Blooms in Moreton,
run by a man called Derek Ward.
And you think Bobby Tanner is in there?
Yes.
And Derek Ward?
Mm, I strongly suspect you will never see
Bobby Tanner and Derek Ward
in the same room together.
[exhales] Apparently, Bobby Tanner
cuts his enemies' fingers off.
Hm? Oh, my dear girl.
I've seen a hell of a lot worse than that.
[bell tinkling]
[woman] Hello. Can I help you?
Hello. I called earlier
about an order for a wedding.
Is Derek Ward here?
Uh, downstairs.
[mysterious music continues]
Hm.
Bishop to E6.
-What are you planning here, Bogdan?
-[laughing]
This is one of those things
you want to know but have to guess.
[chuckling] You're right.
Um… actually, there is something else
I want to ask you.
-Do you mind if I run it by you?
-Of course.
The first chap who was murdered,
the, um… the builder.
Um, that…
Oh, God, no.
No, his name escapes me.
-Tony Curran.
-That's the chap, the very chap.
Well, from everything I've heard,
I think I might know who killed him.
-[mysterious music playing]
-[shears clipping]
How can I help?
[Elizabeth] I'd like
to introduce myself, Derek.
Um, sorry, can I call you Derek,
or do you prefer Bobby?
Elizabeth Best.
I wondered when you'd drop by.
[water sloshing in vase]
Did you have Ian Ventham
and Tony Curran murdered?
Straight to the point.
Did you?
So you could get their shares
in Coopers Chase?
[inhales deeply]
No, my dears.
I did not have them murdered.
I wanted to though.
Where were you
at the time of Tony Curran's murder?
I was at the Dorchester Hotel,
preparing the floral arrangements
for Prince Khalid Al-Berro's
21st birthday party.
I have at least 200 witnesses
that can confirm this.
So this isn't a cover?
[scoffs] You really are a florist?
Oh, arranging fresh flowers,
pruning them,
it's my one true passion.
The only honest thing about me.
We've got information you now have
sole ownership of Coopers Chase.
Unfortunately, yes.
It's no longer an investment
I'm interested in pursuing.
So, what do you intend to do with it?
Sell the land as fast as I can,
for as much as I can.
[pruning continues]
You know,
I listen when Elizabeth talks, Bogdan.
And it seems to me that… [exhales sharply]
Well, you were
in a difficult situation yourself, hm?
With your mother?
[Bogdan exhales]
Yeah.
Knight to E4.
You know, I don't wish to be rude, Bogdan,
but did you kill Tony Curran?
[chuckles softly]
You think I kill Tony Curran?
Yes, I do, old boy.
I do, I'm afraid.
[chuckles]
[Stephen] Knight to E2.
Donna, would you mind stepping outside
for just a moment?
-[softly] What are you up to?
-Don't worry, I'll be fine.
[shears clipping]
[exhales]
So,
you value your privacy.
Are you threatening me?
I wouldn't advise it.
We picked up another three Polish workers
in Amsterdam this morning, boss.
Here's their passports…
You're picking up workers in Amsterdam?
And why is he giving you
their passports, Bobby?
Safekeeping.
Yes, shock horror.
We're businessmen.
You know bringing people
into this country to work illegally
and then taking their IDs
when they arrive,
oh, that is very, very much
against the law, Bobby.
That'll give you 25 years
at His Majesty's pleasure,
at the very least.
[sniffing]
So… how about this?
You knock this whole operation
on the head.
The passports, the workers.
And you sell Coopers Chase to a bidder
of my choosing, at market value,
and in return, I will keep your identity
and your location a secret.
I'd best not get any smell
of police around here.
I expect you
to deal with our little friend in uniform.
'Cause if you don't, I will.
If any harm comes to my friend Donna,
I will personally be laying a dozen
blood-red roses on your coffin.
I mean, I…
I don't know why you killed Tony.
Perhaps you had good reason.
But I do know you did it.
[softly] You're a clever man, Stephen.
I'm guessing you didn't leave any clues.
You have to understand, Stephen,
it was an accident.
I had no intention of killing Tony.
I only want my passport.
You have to understand that.
You have to believe me, Stephen.
Stephen.
Hm?
[clock chiming]
Uh… Oh, God, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, boy, uh…
[exhaling] Oh, God.
What were we talking about?
You were telling me about, uh, history.
-[inhales] Ah.
-Yeah.
-You want some more tea?
-Oh, yes. Yes, lovely.
Thank you.
One sugar. Oh, no.
Elizabeth's not here.
Four sugars. [chuckles]
So, do we have a deal?
[intriguing music playing]
Deal.
[sniffing]
Just now you said, "We… are businessmen."
Who's "we"?
My business partner, Tony Curran.
Rest in peace.
Tony Curran was involved
in this tawdry little scheme
with the passports?
We divided the workers between us.
Some stayed here, driving trucks,
delivering flowers for me.
Tony brought the others to Coopers Chase.
These are human beings
we're talking about.
At least I gave my workers
their passports back, every now and again,
let them visit their families.
Not Tony. Power-hungry sod.
He'd rarely give them
their passports back, if ever.
[exhales]
-Oh, Christ. [exhales]
-[mysterious music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[engine revving]
Call everyone, Donna.
Ron, Ibrahim, Joyce, Hudson.
-Do it now. We need backup.
-Where?
Coopers Chase, my flat.
We'll be there in seven minutes.
-Drink it while it's hot.
-Thank you.
-Lovely.
-[clears throat]
[suspenseful music intensifies]
[sirens wailing]
[panting]
Stephen, don't drink that.
It could be poisoned.
-What? What… What are you talking about?
-You drank it.
Oh, God. Oh, God, Donna.
-[groaning]
-[grunting]
Going somewhere?
-Not today, I'm afraid.
-Watch it, son.
-[grunts]
-[groaning]
[chuckles] You never lose it.
[grunting]
[gasping]
Joyce, Bogdan may have poisoned Stephen.
Oh!
He's all right.
His pulse is good.
But we must get him checked out properly.
I'll call the duty doctor.
Yeah.
[panting]
Bogdan Jankowski,
I'm placing you under arrest
on the suspicion
of the murder of Tony Curran.
You have no evidence, huh? I said nothing.
Stephen, sometimes he does not know
what he's saying. He can't remember.
[Elizabeth] Wait.
If you said anything to Stephen,
he doesn't need to remember.
Uh, what are you talking about?
Why don't you just let us finish the game?
Stephen records all of his chess games.
[tape rewinding]
[Stephen] Knight to E4.
He likes to listen to it later
to figure out your strategy.
-[tape rewinding]
-[clicking]
[Bogdan] I had no intention
of killing Tony.
I only want my passport.
You have to understand that.
You have to believe me, Stephen.
[clicking]
Oh, Bogdan.
Why did you do it?
It was an accident.
I only want my passport.
Hm? Tony take it, so I went to his house.
But he refused to give it back to me.
He won't listen.
Then he get angry with me. He attack me.
You know, I had to defend myself.
It was him or me. I had no choice.
So, yes, I… I killed Tony.
But I didn't mean to do it.
I didn't mean for it to happen. I'm sorry.
And you didn't poison Stephen, did you?
Of course I don't poison Stephen, no.
He's… He's my friend.
Yes. Yes, I know.
-[tender music playing]
-[chuckles]
Right, get him out of here.
[exhales]
["LoveDrug" by Lady Gaga playing]
♪ I don't wanna feel
I don't wanna cry ♪
♪ So I'm gonna dance until I feel… ♪
[Joyce] Oh! [yells]
-[Ron cheers]
-[Ibrahim] How long has he been doing it?
-Six months, a year.
-[Ibrahim] He's so relaxed.
I know,
but he doesn't look nervous at all.
-I love that bit.
-I'm nervous.
[chuckling]
-[Ron] Makes me nervous.
-[Joyce] He's like a ballet dancer.
-[Ron] He is, isn't he?
-[Joyce] Oh, look at that.
-I love that bit.
-[Ron] Oh, look at that.
-[Joyce] But how does he land, though?
-[Ibrahim] And keep smiling. And relaxed.
[Ron] It makes me nervous.
♪ I just need a hit of your lovedrug ♪
-Look at that landing. Yes!
-Oh! That's my boy!
-[laughing]
-Bravo. Bravo.
-Ronnie, bravo.
-[Ron] Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
-Oh my God.
-[intriguing music playing]
-[Ibrahim] Bravo.
-[Ron] Thank you.
[intriguing music continues]
Sorry to barge in on you like this, John.
[laughs] The gang's all here.
To what do we owe the pleasure?
John, I found this file.
This is our current cold case,
the woman in white.
Tucked away, hidden.
And Penny never suggested we look at it.
Why do you think that might be?
[heart monitor beeping]
Do you remember
the case of Angela Hughes, Pen?
She was killed during a burglary.
Stabbed by a masked intruder,
then fell from her bedroom window.
[Joyce] Only,
there was no masked intruder.
Angela's boyfriend, Peter Mercer,
was the real killer.
The police never charged him
because they believed his story.
Well, they liked him.
He was one of the boys.
But you knew differently, didn't you, Pen?
You knew he was guilty.
You could see that clearly.
Penny killed Peter Mercer,
didn't she, John?
She knew he'd get away with it,
so she found him and she killed him.
And then she hid his body at the cemetery.
And I believe you helped her.
And those were the bones
that Bogdan dug up, inadvertently.
You told me yourself you used to go
to mass with Father Mackie in the '70s.
So that connects you both to the cemetery
at the time that Peter Mercer vanished.
But you know, what gave it away
were the crime scene photos.
Because Penny is in all of them.
-So what does that prove?
-Nothing, officially. But look.
Look at the way
she's looking at Peter Mercer.
Her expression.
We both know
that when Penny has that look,
she's about to take some serious action.
Penny couldn't stand by
and look at that bully get away with it.
She'd seen too many abusers walk free.
I do understand, John. I do. But it's…
it's murder.
You killed Ian Ventham, John.
And you knew if Ian Ventham dug up
that body, the whole story might unravel.
So Ventham had to go, to protect Penny.
I would've done the same.
You keep a few syringes in that drawer,
don't you, John? I've seen them.
-[drawer opening]
-[rummaging]
What's in these syringes, John?
Is it a massive dose of fentanyl?
And you'd know how to use it,
wouldn't you?
Because you've been a vet your whole life.
[tender music playing]
I love Penny so…
so much.
But what use am I to her?
I sit here all day, every day.
Read to her, hold her hand.
Kiss her goodnight.
But I can't make her well.
I can't bring her back.
There was one thing I could do.
You could protect her.
And in the end, I couldn't even do that.
[John breathes deeply]
You'll have to tell the police, of course.
Can you…
Can you just give me
a little time with Penny?
As a friend.
Before you call it in.
Of course.
We'll leave you to say your last goodbyes.
Together.
Thank you.
Oh, Pen.
I will miss you.
Sweet dreams, darling.
What a chase.
[melancholy music playing]
[Elizabeth] So, the Thursday Murder Club
has solved the cold case of Angela Hughes,
the woman in white.
We found the answers we were looking for.
But was it worth the cost?
The grief?
The loss?
[Ibrahim] We are made of love,
you and I,
of that there is no doubt.
When I look at the people gathered here,
I see the love.
Of a father for his son.
Of a mother for her daughter.
Of a wife for the husband she clings to.
I also see the powerful love
of friendship.
New friendship.
Unlikely friendship.
The kind of friendship that makes a man,
after years of wandering,
finally feel he belongs.
Sometimes good people do bad things.
But what John did, he did for love.
For the love of Penny.
And their enduring love
will span time and space,
dancing into the stars together.
We shall miss them.
And we shall remember them always.
[indistinct chatter]
Ibrahim,
that was a beautiful eulogy.
[softly] Thank you for taking my place.
Anytime, my dear.
I wouldn't have got through
a single sentence.
Yeah.
-Joyce?
-Yes?
This is for you.
Oh.
It was Penny's.
But we want you to have it now.
[Ron chuckles]
Welcome to the Thursday Murder Club.
Thank you.
It's good to have you officially on board.
Mm-hmm.
Looking forward to working together.
-And don't forget your ABCs.
-What?
Always bring cake.
[all laughing]
Joanna, look.
I've become an official member.
Congratulations, Mum.
Remember when you moved in here,
and I told you I thought it was a mistake?
Mm.
I was wrong.
First time for everything.
I didn't think
I'd see you happy again after Dad died.
And it's thanks to Elizabeth
and to Ron
and Ibrahim.
And it's thanks to Coopers Chase.
Well, why don't you buy it?
-Excuse me?
-I've heard it's for sale.
-From whom?
-A florist.
What do you think?
Keep us all in our homes?
-[curious music playing]
-[Ron] Mm-hmm.
I think that's a very intriguing proposal.
-Hm.
-[Joanna] Let's talk.
-[clicks tongue] Oh, Joanna. [inhales]
-[Joanna] Mum.
-[Joyce and Joanna chuckle]
-[tender music playing]
-Thank you.
-Mm.
["Wild World" by Cat Stevens playing]
♪ Oh, baby, baby, it's a wild world… ♪
[rattling]
-Happy anniversary, darling. [chuckles]
-Happy anniversary. To another year.
["Oh Very Young" by Cat Stevens playing]
Shall we dance?
-Why not?
-[chuckling] Come on, let's dance.
Life's too short not to dance.
♪ Oh very young
What will you leave us this time? ♪
[Stephen hums]
♪ You're only dancing on this earth
For a short while ♪
♪ And though your dreams
May toss and turn you now ♪
♪ They will vanish away
Like your daddy’s best jeans ♪
♪ Denim blue fading up to the sky ♪
[giggling]
♪ And though you want them to last forever
You know they never will ♪
♪ You know
They never will… ♪
[Ron] Look at this.
You've got to get over here and see this.
It's such a joke.
-Yeah, what can I tell you?
-Cheers.
-Here you go.
-All right. All the best.
-[laughs] Look at that.
-He's given him a second.
-Oh. Well.
-Jeez. He don't stand a chance, does he?
-Cheers, Dad.
-Cheers. All the best.
-Mmm.
-[laughs]
Old-fashioned frames.
I was very young when I got married.
I don't think
Joanna's ever gonna get married.
Gerry was so nervous,
but what a sweet man he was. Hm.
♪ Will you ride
The great white bird into heaven? ♪
♪ And though you want to last… ♪
[Joyce] Oh, Ibrahim, look at you.
-How old were you there?
-22 with hair.
[Joyce laughs]
Still handsome though.
♪ Oh very young
What will you leave us this time? ♪
♪ You're only dancing on this earth
For a short while ♪
♪ Oh very young
What will you leave us this time? ♪
[song fades]
[intriguing music playing]
[invigorating music playing]
[music fades]
[mysterious music playing]